Hello, everyone.
My name is Wei Chung from Futurewei Technologies.
Today we're going to go over what
the Wonderland Engine is,
it's main features and how to build your own VR experience
using the Wonderland Engine.
From this video, you will learn
how to set up your development environment
the different parts of the Wonderland
Editor UI.
Getting started with a new VR project
and adding in objects.
Applying JavaScript components to your objects.
How to change the camera. view, the scene lighting and enabling cast of shadows.
Then we'll get into the design goals
of our specific demos and its JavaScript game components.
We also include how to debug a game
from the Huawei VR Glass, and lastly,
rendering support
for simplified Chinese characters.
The Wonderland Engine is a development platform for web-based graphic applications, specifically for VR and AR.
It comes with an accessible 3D editor application, the Wonderland Editor and efficient Webassembly runtime that runs in the browser.
The Wonderland engine enables you to easily build
highly performant VR and AR applications for the web.
Before we can begin creating a new Wonderland project, please use the QR code or URL to create an account.
Download and install Wonderland Engine
The Wonderland Editor is only for making
changes to the 3D environment.
A separate code editor is needed to edit
the JavaScript files
and we recommend
using Visual Studio Code for this.
You can follow the QR code or URL to download it.
In addition to a code editor,
you're going to need a full
VR browser app to run the game on
your Huawei phone.
The Wolvic VR browser is the only VR capable
browser created for the Huawei VR Glass.
Please download Wolvic VR Browser 6DoF version
from wolvic.com/dl
Before moving on to the next step, let me introduce you to Bryant and he will explain the code development.
Hello, everyone. I'm Bryant from Futurewei Technologies.
Here's what the layout for the Wonderland
Editor looks like,
which is similar to a streamlined 3D
model editor.
The scene view displays
a preview of the 3D environment.
All objects can be viewed
and managed from the Scene Outline.
That Asset Browser allows for drag-and-drop.
Importation of assets into the project.
Individual object properties
can be changed from the Properties view.
The Console can be viewed from the bottom right for debugging. You can package and start
your game server or from the top center of the window.
Now that we've got all the tools installed and our environment setup, let's create
a new Wonderland project.
From the Welcome Screen, Select New > VR template and Create to open up a new project.
We start the project off
by importing all the 3D models needed.
This can be done by first dragging and dropping the files directly into the model folder of the Asset Browser,
and then dropping them
into the scene view.
If you need to remove an object from the scene, right-click it from the Scene Outline and select the Delete option.
It will still be available in the Asset Browser.
Object transformation can be done
from either the Scene or Properties views.
Modifications made from the scene view are best for coarse changes
while the Properties view
allows for greater precision changes.
Additionally, the Properties view
can be used to change JS component values.
The Properties view not only allows for changing the values
for JS components,
but components can also be added
to objects from this view as well.
To remove JS components from an object,
click the three-dot icon and select the delete option.
To change the camera view of a scene, we can zoom using the scroll wheel pan by
right-clicking and dragging, or rotate by holding the middle mouse button and dragging.
To add a new light object, navigate to Scene Outline, right-click Root > Add Object and then Light. With a light object,
we can change its transformation,
light intensity, color and light type in properties view.
There are three different light types
available Point, Spot and Sun.
Each option has different advantages and disadvantages
depending on desired use case.
If you want to illuminate the entire scene, it's best for performance to use a single sunlight
instead of multiple point lights.
Some objects in the scene might not cast shadows
as expected. To fix this problem,
navigate to the properties view and check for the material name that your object is using.
Then navigate to Views > Resources
on the top-left of the window.
Since we know the material name, check which pipeline
correlates to the material of your 3D object.
Finally, go to the Pipeline tab, select your pipeline,
enable Cache Shadows
and disable both ALPHA and
ALPHA_MASKED settings.
This should enable cast of shadows
for your object.
Now that we have all the basics
of the Wonderland Editor down,
we're going to move into the details
of our game demo. The design goal
of our game is to create an engaging and
dynamic experience as a showcase for VR.
We decided to make a shooter
game as it best fit for these requirements.
The game takes place on a farm,
has become overrun with mice,
rejected the game to do some pest control
and save the farm.
The players task moving around the farm
and shooting all the mice to win the game.
Aside from all the 3D assets that need to be imported,
we also have to add in Javascript
to define how all the objects interact
with each other and build a game logic.
Let's dive into the various
JavaScript components that our game uses.
We have an invisible target spawner object
that moves around
randomly and spawns the mice at
set intervals.
The mice are randomly spawned
nearest to the last mouse spawn
based on the movement behavior
of the target spawner object.
The players able to shoot projectiles
because of the bullet spawner component,
which spawns bullet objects and attaches
bullet physics to each one.
The bullet physics component
controls the trajectory of the bullet and the bullet life cycle.
Both the mice
and the bullets have collision components
configured to detect
when they were hit by each other.
Each bullet
also has a score trigger component
which listens for a collision event
with the mouse and triggers a score event.
Additionally, we use audio to
play sound effects and music
To apply JavaScript to our Wonderland project,
we need to use a separate code editor like Visual Studio Code to make the actual code changes.
The JavaScript defines the behavior
of individual objects such as movement,
objects spawning, adding or removing
components, collision effects, etc..
Here we have the mouse spawner object instead of having all the mice spawn in at the same time.
We wanted the spawn locations
to be a little bit more random
and more fun to the player
because this is just the mouse spawner
and not the actual mouse targets
that the player shoots.
We don't want the player
to see where this object is.
As you can see from both the Scene
and Properties view,
the mouse spawner is rendered invisible
because a mesh component is set inactive
other than an inactive mesh that affects
how the object looks in the game.
There are two other components
that determine the behavior.
These components control
how the mice is spawned
and how the spawner itself moves
around the map.
Mouse spawner and spawn mover.
Now, we'll take a look at the JavaScript files
for the mouse spawner object.
Here we have the actual code for the mouse
spawner component.
At the top of the file. We define the global variables that can be accessed by all the other JS files.
This can be quite useful, but not recommended for all variables you might use in your project.
Right after the component name declaration, we can define variables here with values that can be changed from the Properties
view in the Wonderland Editor. This type of variable declaration is most useful for mesh, material and animation types,
init() is the first function
called in the component lifecycle.
We initialize the rest of the variables here and also initialize the mouse sound effect.
The start function is always called after the init() function
has completed.
Whether or not you decide to use the start
function is up to you.
Here we make the first call to the spawn
target function which spanws the first mouse
at the beginning of the game.
The update function is called
for every frame update.
For example, 60 frames per second means that the update function is called 60 times per second.
In general, it makes sense
to update the position of moving objects.
Listen for collision events, time sensitive events, and anything that relies on time here
For the mouse spawner, we check the time
elapsed and spawn the mice at set intervals
until the maximum number of mice is reached.
In the spawn target function,
we create a new object, set its position relative to the current spawner location and set its size.
Then we add the mesh, spawn mover, collision and score trigger components. For a final touch,
We play the mouse sound effect as a cue to the player
that the new mouse has spawned in.
The blue spawner component is attached
to the controller and listens
for input from the trigger and access
the fire control for new bullet objects.
Moving forward, we're just going to focus on
the more significant portion of the code.
onTouchDown is called
when the controller trigger is depressed
the onActivate and xrSessionStart functions are used to bind
the select start events to onTouchDown
before everything else loads.
To control the player's rate of fire,
we do a check for the first time
since the last shot occurred.
If enough time has passed,
we get the forward vector
of the controller's cursor
to determine the direction that the bullet
should travel in
and pass it into the launch function.
To provide better haptic feedback to the player, pulse is call to vibrate the controller on every shot.
Launch (throw) does a few checks before calling spawnBullet.
spawnBullet adds a new object for the bullet, sizes it to the correct scale, adds a mesh, collision
and bullet physics components.
Control of the bullet trajectory is done
in just a few lines in bullet physics.
Most of the work in physics is done
in the update function, since we expect the ball
to be in constant motion.
If the bullet hits the floor,
we deactivate the object to preserve performance.
If the bullet travels
too far from the player beyond the load
distance we also deactivate it.
Otherwise, the bullet continues to travel in a straight path from where it was shot at a constant speed.
Each bullet has a score trigger component attached to it, which detects if it has collided with the mouse
while the bullet is still active.
Inside of init,
We load the audio sound effects
and play them later.
We want the score trigger to check for collisions
whenever the bullet updates its position.
Therefore, we also do the checks for
score trigger inside of update.
If a collision is detected, we trigger
the confetti particles, destroy the mouse
object, update the score message
and play a hit sound effect.
If all the mice have been eliminated,
the score message changes to show a win,
the background music and mouse
sound effect stop and the win music plays
All the background sound effects and music
are implemented in bgMusic,
which is attached to the player object.
This means that the audio volume from these sources stays constant no matter where the player moves.
As you can see, initializing and playing sounds is quite simple and takes only two lines of code per audio source.
If others JS components need access to this audio, it just needs to be declared as a global variable, instead of a local one.
With that,
we've covered the code development.
Thanks, Bryant. Before we wrap up this video, let's look at some extra features and debug set up
The Wonderland Engine supports rendering
of Simplified Chinese characters.
You can incorporate Simplified Chinese fonts into your project by following the tutorial found on the Wonderland Engine website.
When using the Huawei VR class,
it is not possible to connect the phone
via USB and debug the Wonderland game while it is running on the device.
This is because there is no available
USB port on the phone as it is taken up by the VR glass.
Instead, we have to use ADB over Wi-Fi
to connect to the Huawei phone
This can be done by enabling ADB
over a Wi-Fi on the Huawei phone,
configuring the SSL server on the Wonderland Editor and using localhost:8081 instead of localhost:8080
to connect to the Wonderland local server.
You can follow the guide
to set up your development environment.
That conclude our presentation
on the Wonderland Engine demo.
Here are the links for the free
and complete game source code.
The Wonderland Engine itself, the Wolvic
VR Browser and check out our website
running a live instance of the game.
Thank you.