Hello everyone! My name is Wei Chung from Futurewei Technologies.
Today we’re going to go over what the Wonderland Engine is, its main features,
and an introduction to how to build your own VR experience using the Wonderland Engine.
From this video, you will learn how to set up your development environment, the different part of the Wonderland Editor UI,
Getting started with a new VR project, and adding in objects, applying Javascript components to your objects
modify the Scene view, apply Javascript logic to the scene, and lastly, how to debug a game from the Huawei VR Glass
The Wonderland Engine is a development platform for web-based graphic applications, specifically for VR and AR.
It comes with an accessible 3D editor application, the Wonderland Editor and efficient Webassembly runtime that runs in the browser.
The Wonderland engine enables you to easily build
highly performant VR and AR applications for the web.
Before we can begin creating a new Wonderland project, please use the QR code or URL to create an account.
Download and install Wonderland Engine
The Wonderland Editor is only for making
changes to the 3D environment.
A separate code editor is needed to edit
the JavaScript files
and we recommend
using Visual Studio Code for this.
You can follow the QR code or URL to download it.
In addition to a code editor,
you're going to need a full
VR browser app to run the game on
your Huawei phone.
The Wolvic VR browser is the only VR capable
browser created for the Huawei VR Glass.
Please download Wolvic VR Browser 6DoF version
from wolvic.com/dl
Before moving on to the next step, let me introduce you to Bryant and he will explain the code development.
Hello, everyone. I'm Bryant from Futurewei Technologies.
Here's what the layout for the Wonderland
Editor looks like,
which is similar to a streamlined 3D
model editor.
The scene view displays
a preview of the 3D environment.
All objects can be viewed
and managed from the Scene Outline.
That Asset Browser allows for drag-and-drop.
Importation of assets into the project.
Individual object properties
can be changed from the Properties view.
The Console can be viewed from the bottom right for debugging. You can package and start your game server or from the top center of the window.
Now that we've got all the tools installed and our environment setup, let's create
a new Wonderland project.
From the Welcome Screen, Select New > VR template and Create to open up a new project.
We start the project off
by importing all the 3D models needed.
This can be done by first dragging and dropping the files directly into the model folder of the Asset Browser,
and then dropping them
into the scene view.
If you need to remove an object from the scene, right-click it from the Scene Outline and select the Delete option.
It will still be available in the Asset Browser.
Object transformation can be done
from either the Scene or Properties views.
Modifications made from the scene view are best for coarse changes
while the Properties view
allows for greater precision changes.
Additionally, the Properties view
can be used to change JS component values.
The Properties view not only allows for changing the values
for JS components,
but components can also be added
to objects from this view as well.
To remove JS components from an object,
click the three-dot icon and select the delete option.
To change the camera view of a scene, we can zoom using the scroll wheel pan by
right-clicking and dragging, or rotate by holding the middle mouse button and dragging.
To apply JavaScript to our Wonderland project,
we need to use a separate code editor like Visual Studio Code to make the actual code changes.
The JavaScript defines the behavior
of individual objects such as movement,
objects spawning, adding or removing
components, collision effects, etc..
When using the Huawei VR class,
it is not possible to connect the phone
via USB and debug the Wonderland game while it is running on the device.
This is because there is no available
USB port on the phone as it is taken up by the VR glass.
Instead, we have to use ADB over Wi-Fi
to connect to the Huawei phone
This can be done by enabling ADB
over a Wi-Fi on the Huawei phone,
configuring the SSL server on the Wonderland Editor and using localhost:8081 instead of localhost:8080
to connect to the Wonderland local server.
You can follow the guide
to set up your development environment.
That conclude our presentation
on the Wonderland Engine demo.
Here are the links for the free
and complete game source code.
The Wonderland Engine itself, the Wolvic
VR Browser and check out our website
running a live instance of the game.
Thank you.